Fred Crawford Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 12. Audio Recordings, 12; Boxes: 189 - 192
  - Subseries 12.5: Recorded by Rick Moulton, 12.5; Box: 190
    - Tape #3 and Tape #4 Lowell Thomas 3/17/81 (Picketts, Hero of RAD - - _____, Hitler Comment, knew Mussolini, lists injuries), 1981 March 17 (Folder 4, Box 190)
    - Tape #5 Lowell Thomas Broadcasts, undated (Folder 5, Box 190)
    - Tape #6 and Tape #7 Lowell Thomas 3/17/81 5 " reel tape STEPP on Skiing, 1981 March 17 (Folder 6, Box 190)
    - Tape #8 and Tape #9 Lowell Thomas (Sepp & Lowell, Stowe, Sun Valley, Whiteface), undated (Folder 7, Box 190)
    - Note: These are the cassette recording I made of Mary Brady's reminiscences L.T. said he would be interested in having your man make copies of them. I made them on used cassettes and the 6th side is a recording of a sermon by a Baptist minister in Australia. I don't need it back. Mary Brady 1 of 3., undated (Folder 8, Box 190)
    - [see note] Mary Brady 2 of 3., undated (Folder 9, Box 190)
    - [see note] Mary Brady 3 of 3., undated (Folder 10, Box 190)
  - Subseries 12.6: Microcassette recordings made by Fred Crawford, 12.6; Box: 190
    - Garst [Museum], Marianna [Marianna Munn Thomas], 1996 August (Folder 11, Box 190)
    - Jim Morrison, Phil Gauthier, undated (Folder 12, Box 190)
    - A - Marist tape notes 1 (transcribed), undated (Folder 13, Box 190)
    - Stan - Rolls Royce, Marianna [Marianna Munn Thomas] TCT 14/8/91, 1991 (Folder 14, Box 190)
    - Garst notes October visit, Toni [Toni Matt] on LT death, undated (Folder 15, Box 190)
    - Pawling notes, 1991 August 4 - 7 (Folder 16, Box 190)
    - University of Denver - Penrose, Hack [Hack Miller] BYU part 1 and 2, undated (Folder 17, Box 190)
    - Unlabeled microcassette, undated (Folder 18, Box 190)
    - Unlabeled microcassette, undated (Folder 19, Box 190)
    - Fred Crawford's microcassette recorder, undated (Folder 20, Box 190)
  - Subseries 12.7: Recordings about Lowell Thomas, 12.7; Boxes: 190 - 191
    - The Fifties by David Halberstam, #1 and #2, read by Edwin Newman, Random House Audio, 1993 (Folder 21, Box 190)
    - The Fifties by David Halberstam, #3 and #4, read by Edwin Newman, Random House Audio, 1993 (Folder 1, Box 191)
    - The Fifties by David Halberstam, #5 and #6, read by Edwin Newman, Random House Audio, 1993 (Folder 2, Box 191)
    - The Fifties by David Halberstam, #7 and #8, read by Edwin Newman, Random House Audio, 1993 (Folder 3, Box 191)
    - A Tribute to Lowell Thomas, CBS Radio/CBS Television & Funeral 8/29/81 & 9/2/81, 1981 August 29 - September 2 (Folder 4, Box 191)
    - Lowell Thomas Memorial Service, Dr. Gordon Powell and Dr. Ralph Lankler. Christ Church on Quaker Hill, Pawling, NY, 1981 September 3 (Folder 5, Box 191)
    - Janet Reisman, Lowell Thomas and the Creation of the Lawrence Legend, undated (Folder 6, Box 191)
    - T. E. Lawrence By His Friends. Side 1: Matthews to Findley. Side 2: Chambers - Knowles, undated (Folder 7, Box 191)
  - Subseries 12.8: Lowell Thomas recordings, origin unknown, 12.8; Boxes: 191 - 192
    - Side 1: The Fred Allen Show 10/24/1948 Fred Allen attacks radio quiz shows. Side 2: Living 1949 1/30/49 Fred Allen on " The State of American Humor ", 1948 - 1949 (Folder 8, Box 191)
    - Associated Press Luncheon Waldorf - Astoria GBR General Haig Speech 4/23/1979 (signed A. Bart), 1979 April 23 (Folder 9, Box 191)
    - Side 1: Douglas " Wrong War " Corrigan Dinner at the Advertising Club 8/8/1938. Side 2: NBC D - Day Coverage 6/6/1944, 1938 - 1944 (Folder 10, Box 191)
    - Side 1: Flint, Michigan (WFDF Radio) Lowell Thomas 10/26/1977. Side 2: AUC5 3/93 IAH 201 stdmt research (Folder 11, Box 191)
    - Focus (Bush) 4/25/1980, 1980 April 25 (Folder 12, Box 191)
    - Kaltenborn Edits the News (16, 17, 18, 23, and 24 October 1939), 1939 October 16 - 24 (Folder 13, Box 191)
    - Kansas City Press Club Scholarship Benefit Dinner 5/19/1977, 1977 May 19 (Folder 14, Box 191)
    - KFH News Wichita Kansas, undated (Folder 15, Box 191)
    - Lowell Thomas Amenia speech 1977 Sheriff Quinlan's Dinner. Haley botch with Electra / Ansonia 90 (Folder 16, Box 191)
    - Side 1: Lowell Thomas: " The Best Years " cuts 41 - 50 with FDR slam plus Ronald Reagan. Side 2: BB25M (4 - 13) IAH201 Student research, undated (Folder 17, Box 191)
    - Lowell Thomas: " The Best Years " Ed Murrow, Pancho Villa. For Lowell Thomas May 1981 (Stan Jones) Princeton Veteans 1977 Chicago Lowell Thomas and LT 280CT80 Br Reagan and Bush, undated (Folder 18, Box 191)
    - 27. Lowell Thomas, David Brinkley, Jack Anderson, undated (Folder 19, Box 191)
    - Lowell Thomas Dayton no. 2 90, undated (Folder 20, Box 191)
    - Lowell Thomas dictation tape, undated (Folder 21, Box 191)
    - Lowell Thomas as Doolittle Raider Reunion in Memphis 4/9/1977. Also General Doolittle final remarks of banquet on side B, 1977 April 9 (Folder 22, Box 191)
    - Side 1: Lowell Thomas Final Broadcast 5/14/1976. Side 2: Lowell Thomas, Jr. Dutch Treat Club 12/18/1979, 1976 - 1979 (Folder 1, Box 192)
    - Side 1: Lowell Thomas interview by O.M. Ostlund, Jr.and Ross Club (Williamsport, PA) on occasion of LT's induction and honorary head of Woolrich Hall of Fame July 1980. Side 2: AK 5/16/88 (and notes) to 62, 1980 - 1988 (Folder 2, Box 192)
    - Lowell Thomas, Kabul Afghanistan 1 of 3, 1977 March (Folder 3, Box 192)
    - Lowell Thomas, Kabul Afghanistan 2 of 3, 1977 March (Folder 4, Box 192)
    - Lowell Thomas, Kabul Afghanistan 3 of 3, 1977 March (Folder 5, Box 192)
    - Lowell Thomas News Broadcasts on NBC (6:45pm), 1946 September 9 - 13 (Folder 6, Box 192)
    - Side 1: Lowell Thomas News 7/10/1973, 5/14/1976. Side 2: The Fred Allen Show 10/6/1956 with Lowell Thomas and H. V. Kaltenborn, 1956 - 1976 (Folder 7, Box 192)
    - Lowell Thomas Address to the Radio Pioneers Dinner 5/21/1961, 1961 May 21 (Folder 8, Box 192)
    - Side 1: Lowell Thomas Address to the Radio Pioneers Dinner 5/21/1961. Side 2: Lowell Thomas CBS affiliate speech part 1 and 2 9/15/1965., 1961 - 1965 (Folder 9, Box 192)
    - Side 1: Pole to Pole (includes radio transmission from LT to LT Jr.. Lt endorsement of Reagan - Bush; Summer Boy Scout Camp promotion show narrated by LT, Sr. Westchester - Putnam Council. Side 2: Lowell Thomas dictation tape, undated (Folder 10, Box 192)
    - Side 1: Oral history Douglas Storen interviews Lowell Thomas 3/15/1968. Side 2: IRTS Luncheon 10/28/70 50 yeas of radio, Lowell Thomas speaker, 1958 - 1970 (Folder 11, Box 192)
    - NBC Affiliates Banquet Show 6/22/1976, 1976 June 22 (Folder 12, Box 192)
    - Side 1: NBC Affiliates Banquet Show head table 6/22/1976. Side 2: NB 7 - 5 Luncheon Hall of Fame Awards 1977 Conv, NAB, 1976 - 1977 (Folder 13, Box 192)
    - [With note] Pacific Pioneer Broadcasters 3/19/1976, 1976 March 19 (Folder 14, Box 192)
    - Side 1: Pacific Pioneer Broadcasters 3/19/1976. Side 2: 12 .General Alexander Haig. (Folder 15, Box 192)
    - Side 1: Dr. Russel Lee talk at Cave Man Camp 7/28/1978 ( " This one only fair " ). Side 2: Ray Virden, Lowell Thomas, Bob Armbruster, John Chales Thomas, Deems Taylor, Marc Connelly, Gene Lockhart. (Folder 16, Box 192)
    - [With Note] Side 1: Seven Wonders. Side 2: Fine in Alaska, Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr., undated (Folder 17, Box 192)
    - Tribute to Lowell Thomas CBS Radio Network 5/14/1976 1 of 3, 1976 May 14 (Folder 18, Box 192)
    - Tribute to Lowell Thomas CBS Radio Network 5/14/1976 2 of 3, 1976 May 14 (Folder 19, Box 192)
    - Tribute to Lowell Thomas CBS Radio Network 5/14/1976 3 of 3, 1976 May 14 (Folder 20, Box 192)
    - Side 1: " This Is Cinerama " a +t One - intermission Sound Demo, stereo Dolby. Side 2. " This is Cinerama Cypress gardens and America the Beautiful. ", undated (Folder 21, Box 192)
    - We The People, Gabriel Heatter, host, 1940 February 6 - September 3 (Folder 22, Box 192)
- 13. Video Tapes, 13; Boxes: 193 - 196
  Series contains Commercial videocassettes (VHS)and Recorded videocassettes (VHS)
  - Subseries 13.1: Commercial videocassettes (VHS), 13.1; Boxes: 193 - 194
    - From the Film and Video Archive of the Imperial War Museum: With Lawrence in Arabia, circa 1996 (Folder 1, Box 193)
    - From the Film and Video Archive of the Imperial War Museum: Lowell Thomas' Film of Lawrence in Arabia, circa 1996 (Folder 2, Box 193)
    - Lowell Thomas an Alston Callahan, M.D., undated (Folder 3, Box 193)
    - The Cinerama Adventure - Presentation Sample Reel, Temp. Narration & Music (Stereo) 26 Minutes, undated (Folder 4, Box 193)
    - A&E Biography - Lowell Thomas: Man About the World. Color, approx.. 50 min. ISBN 0 - 7670 - 3011 - 7, 1997 (Folder 5, Box 193)
    - Video Images presents a Video Yesteryear recording: 100. BORNEO. (1937) Adventure documentary with MARTIN and OSA JOHNSON. Narrated by LOWELL THOMAS. Featuring " Wildmen of Borneo ", tree - climbing fish, and flying snakes! Recommended! 76 minutes (Folder 6, Box 193)
    - Video Images presents a Video Yesteryear recording: 241. SEE IT NOW (June 9, 1957). CBS - TV. " Automation. " EDWARD R. MURROW narrating. How Automation is changing American industry, unemployment, and the way we live. 82 minutes. [unopened], 1957 June 9 (Folder 7, Box 193)
    - Video Images presents a Video Yesteryear recording: 243. IT'S NEWS TO ME (c. July 1954). CBS - TV net. A young WALTER CRONKITE moderating a panel/game show based on (then) current news events. 30 minutes. [unopened], circa 1954 July (Folder 8, Box 193)
    - Video Images presents a Video Yesteryear recording: 366. THE STORY OF TELEVISION (June 20, 1956) PARTIAL COLOR. Documentary history of TV, including rare scenes of station W2XBS and Dr. VLADIMIR ZWORTKIN! 27 minutes., 1956 June 20 (Folder 9, Box 193)
    - Video Images presents a Video Yesteryear recording: 448. THINGS TO COME. (1936) With RAYMOUND MASSEY, RALPH RICHARDSON, SIR CEDRIC HARDWICK. Written by H.G. WELLS. Spectacular classic of the future. 92 minutes. (Folder 10, Box 193)
    - Video Images presents a Video Yesteryear recording: 485. BEHIND YOUR RADIO DIAL and WESTINGHOUSE PRESENTS (1948). NBC industrial film about " today's " radio, and a complete broadcast on film with JOHN CHARLES THOMAS. 45 minutes total. [unopened] (Folder 1, Box 194)
    - Video Images presents a Video Yesteryear recording: 1157. CONQUEST OF EVEREST (1953) COLOR. The story of Edmund Hillary's conquest of Mount Everest. Named one of the 10 best films of the year! 78 minutes. [unopened] (Folder 2, Box 194)
    - Video Images presents a Video Yesteryear recording: 1212. THE JACK BENNY PROGRAM (October 18, 1959) CBS - TV. With JACK BENNY, DON WILSON, THE SPORTSMEN, former President HARRY TRUMAN. 25 minutes. [unopened], 1959 October 18 (Folder 3, Box 194)
    - Video Images presents a Video Yesteryear recording: 2222. BABOONA (1935 - USA) With MARTIN and OSA JOHNSON, A fine wildlife nature film with the couple who invented the idea of bringing wild animals to the movie screen. Well done! 73 minutes. [unopened] (Folder 4, Box 194)
    - Video Images presents a Video Yesteryear recording: 2261. THE SPIRIT OF " 43 " AND MORE! (1941 - 1950's - USA) PARTIAL COLOR. Four Short films. " The Spirit of " 43, " " The House I Live In, " " Soldiers in Greasepaint, " and " Women in Defense. " 56 minutes total. [unopened] (Folder 5, Box 194)
    - Video Images presents a Video Yesteryear recording: 2280. WITH BYRD AT THE SOUTH POLE(1930 - USA) With ADMIRAL RICHARD BYRD. The beautifully photographed story of the first flight over the South Pole by Byrd and his men. Well done! 83 minutes. [unopened] (Folder 6, Box 194)
    - Video Images presents a Video Yesteryear recording: 2289. SIMBA (1928 - USA) With OSA and MARTIN JOHNSON. A superb example of the work of the famous jungle cinematographers. " Silent " film with music score. 86 minutes. (Folder 7, Box 194)
    - Video Images presents a Video Yesteryear recording: 2524. THE JEEP GOES TO WAR! (1942 - c.1944 - USA) Five government films showing Jeeps, half - tracks and tanks in action. 54 minutes total., 1942 - circa 1944 (Folder 8, Box 194)
    - Video Images presents a Video Yesteryear recording: 2920. A GREAT RAILROAD AT WORK (1942 - USA) Narrated by LOWELL THOMAS. A portrait of the New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad, how it is operated and how it is maintained. 47 minutes. (Folder 9, Box 194)
    - Video Images presents a Video Yesteryear recording: 2993. HEAVY METAL: STUDEBAKER, NASH, HUDSON and KAISER (1952 - 1955 - USA) PARTIAL COLOR. " Nash For 1953/1955, " Hudson commercial, " Studebaker Story " and " Word Of Honor. " 65 minutes total. (Folder 10, Box 194)
  - Subseries 13.2: Recorded videocassettes (VHS), 13.2; Boxes: 195 - 196
    - Lowell Thomas Remembers - #1 of 4, 1930 - 1932 (Folder 1, Box 195)
    - Lowell Thomas Remembers - #2 of 4, 1933 - 1939 (Folder 2, Box 195)
    - Lowell Thomas Remembers - #3 of 4, 1940 - 1944 (Folder 3, Box 195)
    - Lowell Thomas Remembers - #4 of 4, 1945 - 1954 (Folder 4, Box 195)
    - Cataloging of Marist College Collection - Lowell Jackson Thomas (By Bill Booker 11/95) #1 of 2, 1995 (Folder 5, Box 195)
    - Cataloging of Marist College Collection - Lowell Jackson Thomas (By Bill Booker 11/95) #2 of 2, 1995 (Folder 6, Box 195)
    - " In Search of Lawrence " with Michael Asher, broadcast in Britain at 9:00pm, 29 July 1997, channel 4., 1997 July 29 (Folder 7, Box 195)
    - 0:00 - 1:00 (SP) Stan; 1:00 - (SLP) 39 Steps; 2:21 - 3:18 Yeager; 3:18 - LT from[?] Kingfish: A Story of Huey P. Long TBS World Premiere, 1995 March 19 (Folder 8, Box 195)
    - 0:00:00 - (0:55:52) - Royal Yacht Britannia, History of; 0:59:35 - (1:43:37) - Edward on Edward (Prince on King); 2:42:52 - (1:45:26) - Lost Continent of Atlantis Special; 3:28:18 - (0:25:01) - Dayton, Ohio " Shaping Next Century "; 3:53:19 - (0:37:58) - Dayton, Ohio, " Memories (of) "; 4:31:17 - - End; [more description on notes], undated (Folder 9, Box 195)
    - A Dangerous Man 0 - 145; Excerpt - 158; Les Mis 2:48; Simon/, undated (Folder 10, Box 195)
    - David Lean - >~1:40 / 1:59 - > Home Front to 2:28; Doolittle to 3:31 / Animal Crackers 3:35 - 5:04/, undated (Folder 11, Box 195)
    - Christmas in July - 0 - >1:06:50; Tokyo Rose - 1:07 - 1:33; The Astors - 1:33 - 2:33; Brinkley - 2:35 - 3:20; Quints - 3:22 - 4:09, undated (Folder 1, Box 196)
    - 00 - 1:54:00 War Against the Indians; 1:54 - 2:40:54 Lindbergh; 2:41 - 3:40 I Will Fight No More Forever; 3:40 - The Great War (TLC) - (LT), undated (Folder 2, Box 196)
    - 16 September 97 - A&E Biography Dale Carnegie (1hr, EP); 17 November 97 - Ed R. Murrow, 1997 (Folder 3, Box 196)
    - Biography: Walter Cronkite (00:00); Mike Wallace (1:30); David Brinkley (2:17); - (defective[?]) Walter Winchell (3:00); Helen Thomas (3:45); Edward R. Murrow (4:31 - 5:17), undated (Folder 4, Box 196)
    - 0 - 6 of 19[?]: The Master Illusionist; 1:10:56 - York; 1:12 - Footprints: Road to a Legend; 1:42:00 - L of A Newsreels/ L & Arabia [Lawrence of Arabia]; 3:10 - 3:56 - Churchill (3 of 4); 4:00 - 5:50 - The Best of Friends (Whitmore), undated (Folder 5, Box 196)
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. visits Garst Museum for opening of Thomas Wing, 4/6 - 7, 1999; Reception 4/6 - Ribbon Cutting 4/7, 1999 April 4 - 6 (Folder 6, Box 196)
    - Legends of American Skiing (78 min, SP), undated (Folder 7, Box 196)
    - Lowell Thomas: Man About the World, A&E Biography with Fred D. Crawford, undated (Folder 8, Box 196)
    - 0 - > 46:15 Marconi, undated (Folder 9, Box 196)
    - 0 - 57:24 The Great Air Race of 1924; 57:30 - 1:00:27 Tibet Exhibit (Marist,1989)l 1:00:29 - 2:32:11 Lawrence and Arabia (SL), undated (Folder 10, Box 196)
    - BBC TEL [T.E. Lawrence] (1962) 0:59:26; 59:22 This Is Your Life 0:59:27; 1:28:43 LT in Victor 1:28:44; Wilson + War 1:39:40 - 2:04:52; TEL [T. E. Lawrence] footage 2:04:25; Main Top 2:11:00 - 2:20, undated (Folder 11, Box 196)